Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
The visitors are all guests.
الزوار جميعهم ضيوف
You missed the feast,
فاتك العيد
I'll make it up for you.
سوف أعوضها لك.
Ouyang Xi, serve the wine.
Ouyang Xi ، قدمي النبيذ.
It's Old Master.
إنه المعلم القديم.
Please
لو سمحت
I'll do it first as a toast.
سأفعل ذلك أولاً كنخب.
Xin Mei,
شين مي ،
Please.
لو سمحت.
In front of everyone,
أمام الجميع،
you'd better leave some retreat for yourself.
من الأفضل أن تترك ملاذًا لنفسك.
As early as 24 years ago,
منذ 24 عامًا ،
when I climbed out of the dead,
عندما خرجت من الموتى ،
I didn't give myself a way out.
لم أعطي نفسي مخرجًا.
In those two stones,
في هاتين الحجرتين ،
it was so easy for you to distinguish between true and false.
كان من السهل عليك التمييز بين الصواب والخطأ.
But you were so indiscriminate
لكنك كنت عشوائيا جدا
that you insisted that the piece my father took was fake,
أنك أصررت على أن القطعة التي أخذها أبي كانت مزيفة ،
Have you really never doubted the Xue family
هل حقا لم تشك في عائلة Xue
in charge of Luoshi?
المسؤول عن Luoshi؟
The Xue family and our Zerg Five Clans are in the same breath,
عائلة Xue وعشائرنا Zerg Five في نفس الوقت ،
Your father, Lord He,
والدك يارب
escorted our Zerg family and humiliated the entire tribe in Bamen Mountain.
اصطحبنا عائلتنا الزرق وأذلوا القبيلة بأكملها في جبل بامين.
When your father gave Luo Shi,
عندما أعطى والدك لوه شي ،
it was a plot
كانت مؤامرة
to uproot the Zerg.
لاقتلاع الزرج.
Heaven has no eyes and evil people get what they want,
ليس للسماء عيون والأشرار يحصلون على ما يريدون ،
Bamen Mountain is bleeding profusely.
ينزف جبل بامين بغزارة.
today
اليوم
The death of the Zerg is all thanks to you.
موت الزرج كل الشكر لكم.
Nonsense.
كلام فارغ.
Grandpa, that's not what happened.
جدي ، هذا ليس ما حدث.
Senior Ouyang,
كبار أويانغ ،
look at the letter in your hand.
انظر إلى الرسالة التي في يدك.
That's a letter written by Clan Leader Xue himself,
هذه رسالة كتبها Clan Leader Xue نفسه ،
which contains everything that happened.
الذي يحتوي على كل ما حدث.
You wronged her.
أنت ظلمتها.
As a gentleman of the Department of Wood,
كرجل نبيل من قسم الخشب ،
I guarantee, Senior Ouyang,
أنا أضمن ، أويانغ كبير ،
Back then,
في ذلك الوقت،
the Luo Shi provided by the He family was indeed
كان لوه شي الذي قدمته عائلة هو بالفعل
the river stone handed over by the real Xue family was fake.
كان حجر النهر الذي سلمته عائلة شيويه الحقيقية مزيفًا.
Did you hear that?
هل سمعت هذا؟
You saw it, didn't you?
رأيت ذلك ، أليس كذلك؟
You were wrong back then.
كنت مخطئا في ذلك الوقت.
You're the one who deserves to die.
أنت من يستحق الموت.
The one who deserves to be tortured by thousands of insects
من يستحق أن يعذب آلاف الحشرات
is also your grandfather,
هو أيضا جدك ،
Mother,
الأم،
Yan Ying.
يان ينغ.
Grandpa,
الجد
are you really going to be so cruel?
هل حقا سوف تكون قاسية جدا؟
Are you going to kill my mother?
هل ستقتل والدتي؟
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
it's been 20 years,
لقد مرت 20 سنة ،
I hate that iron can't be made into steel,
أنا أكره أن الحديد لا يمكن تحويله إلى صلب ،
until today you have the blood.
حتى اليوم لديك الدم.
It's a pity that you're confused.
من المؤسف أنك في حيرة من أمرك.
The gun in your hand is pointing at the wrong person.
يشير المسدس الذي في يدك إلى الشخص الخطأ.
Get out of my way!
ابتعد عن طريقي!
Grandpa.
الجد.
If you want to kill my mother,
إذا كنت تريد أن تقتل والدتي ،
kill me first.
اقتلني اولا.
Do you think
هل تعتقد
I dare not?
لا أجرؤ؟
Yan Yun, be careful.
يان يون ، كن حذرا.
Ziwu,
Ziu ،
Ziwu.
إنها أغنية.
Stop!
قف!
You go first.
اذهب أولا.
Stop fighting!
وقف القتال!
Ziwu,
Ziu ،
Yan Yun,
يان يون ،
Yanyun, listen to me. Go with grandpa.
يانيون ، استمع إلي.  اذهب مع جدي.
I'm not leaving.
لن أغادر.
Come on, come on,
اقبل اقبل،
Master,
يتقن،
-Hurry up. -Master, let's
-أسرع - بسرعة.  -ماجستير ، دعنا
go. It's too dangerous here.
اذهب.  إنه أمر خطير للغاية هنا.
Yan Yun, go!
يان يون ، انطلق!
Hurry up and save her.
اسرع وانقذها.
Ziwu,
Ziu ،
Get up.
استيقظ.
If I don't let you come,
إذا لم أتركك تأتي ،
do I have to come to make you happy like this?
هل علي أن آتي لأجعلك سعيدا هكذا؟
Ziwu,
Ziu ،
Ziwu, I'm sorry,
Ziwu ، أنا آسف ،
I really didn't expect this to happen.
لم أكن أتوقع أن يحدث هذا حقًا.
Ziwu,
Ziu ،
Ziwu.
إنها أغنية.
They went in the direction of the arsenal,
ذهبوا في اتجاه الترسانة ،
Kim So-mee,
كيم سو مي ،
Let's go.
هيا بنا.
Grandpa,
الجد
Grandpa.
الجد.
Sister,
أخت،
Grandpa and Mom went to the arsenal,
ذهب الجد وأمي إلى الترسانة ،
I really don't want to see anyone get hurt again.
أنا حقًا لا أريد أن أرى أي شخص يتأذى مرة أخرى.
Sister,
أخت،
how is Ziwu?
كيف هي Ziwu؟
Can you save him?
هل يمكنك انقاذه؟
It's all because of you
كله بسببك
that you're giving me lunch.
أنك تعطيني الغداء.
Pan Jun,
بان جون ،
come on,
تعال،
It's already like this.
إنه بالفعل مثل هذا.
Do you want to waste more time?
هل تريد أن تضيع المزيد من الوقت؟
Do your Ouyang family
هل عائلتك اويانغ
still want to bear another blood debt?
ما زلت تريد أن تتحمل دين دم آخر؟
Ziwu, hang in there.
Ziwu ، تشبث هناك.
Pan Jun,
بان جون ،
I volunteered.
تطوعت.
Don't blame Yanyun.
لا تلوم يانيون.
Will you shut your mouth?
هل ستغلق فمك؟
Ouyang Leiyun,
أويانغ ليون ،
decades of grudges,
عقود من الضغائن ،
Let's put an end to it today.
دعونا نضع حدا لذلك اليوم.
No one is allowed to follow us.
لا يسمح لأحد بمتابعتنا.
If I remember correctly,
إذا كنت أتذكر بشكل صحيح،
in your Fire Department's arsenal,
في ترسانة قسم الإطفاء الخاص بك ،
With more than 700 jin of explosives,
مع أكثر من 700 جين من المتفجرات ،
I'm going to die today.
سأموت اليوم.
You have to go on the road with me.
عليك أن تمضي معي في الطريق.
Gentleman, Young Master Yanying,
السيد المحترم ، السيد الشاب يانيينغ ،
you can't go in there.
لا يمكنك الذهاب هناك.
Get out of the way!
ابتعد عن الطريق!
No one is allowed to go in today.
لا أحد مسموح له بالدخول اليوم.
Can you solve the problem inside?
هل يمكنك حل المشكلة في الداخل؟
Can you?
هل تستطيع؟
Gentleman,
انسان محترم،
Inside,
داخل،
It's too dangerous inside.
إنه خطير للغاية في الداخل.
Now, only if Yan Ying and I go in,
الآن ، فقط إذا دخلنا أنا ويين ينغ ،
can we convince them.
هل يمكننا إقناعهم.
Do you want to see everyone die here?
هل تريد أن ترى الجميع يموتون هنا؟
Trust me,
صدقني،
I'll bring them out safely.
سوف أخرجهم بأمان.
Mother,
الأم،
Mother, grandpa,
الأم ، الجد ،
If you insist on killing Grandpa today,
إذا أصررت على قتل جدي اليوم ،
we'll die together in the arsenal.
سنموت معا في الترسانة.
-Who told you to come in? -Get out.
من قال لك أن تأتي؟  -اخرج.
Mother,
الأم،
Don't be afraid. I've been waiting
لا تخافوا.  لقد كنت منتظرا
for the reunion of my mother and son for 20 years.
من أجل لم شمل والدتي وابني لمدة 20 عامًا.
If I can't live with you today,
إذا لم أستطع العيش معك اليوم ،
I'll die with you.
سأموت معك.
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
get out!
اخرج!
Sister, as I said,
اختي كما قلت
if you want to kill my mother, kill me first.
إذا كنت تريد أن تقتل أمي ، اقتلني أولاً.
Senior Lei Yun Boss Jin,
كبير لي يون بوس جين ،
you two don't care about blood and water,
أنتما الاثنان لا تهتمان بالدم والماء ،
Do we have to go all the way to the dark?
هل علينا أن نذهب إلى الظلام؟
Grandpa,
الجد
what you did is hurting both sides.
ما فعلته يؤذي كلا الجانبين.
Wan Jiajun will be the only one who will benefit.
سيكون Wan Jiajun هو الشخص الوحيد الذي سيستفيد.
You have to look at your flesh and blood.
عليك أن تنظر إلى لحمك ودمك.
Blocking the muzzle of the Wan Army with flesh and blood?
سد كمامة جيش وان باللحم والدم؟
Mother,
الأم،
I've been waiting for you for half my life.
لقد كنت في انتظارك لمدة نصف عمري.
He has traveled more than half of the mountains and rivers for you.
سافر من أجلك في أكثر من نصف الجبال والأنهار.
At the top of the mountain and the edge of the world,
على قمة الجبل وعلى حافة العالم ،
he went there for you.
ذهب إلى هناك من أجلك.
He's waiting for you outside Ba Song City right now.
إنه ينتظرك خارج مدينة با سونغ الآن.
Mother,
الأم،
Everyone in Ba Song said,
قال الجميع في با سونغ ،
I was born with a golden spoon in my mouth.
ولدت بملعقة ذهبية في فمي.
I want the wind to win. I want the rain to rain.
أريد الريح أن تفوز.  أريد المطر أن يمطر.
What else can I not be satisfied with?
ما الأشياء الأخرى التي لا يمكنني أن أكون راضيًا عنها؟
However,
لكن،
no one has ever asked me
لم يسألني أحد من قبل
what I really want?
ما اريد حقا؟
I just want you and father to come back.
أنا فقط أريدك أنت وأبي العودة.
I just want a complete family.
أنا فقط أريد عائلة كاملة.
You worthless thing.
أنت شيء لا قيمة له.
I've raised you for 20 years.
لقد ربيتك لمدة 20 عامًا.
It's a waste of time.
انها مضيعة للوقت.
Don't point a gun at my son.
لا توجه مسدسًا إلى ابني.
Okay,
تمام،
Then.
ثم.
I'll give my life for my life,
سأبذل حياتي من أجل حياتي ،
and kill you.
ويقتلك.
Grandpa,
الجد
ever since Yan Yun was born,
منذ ولادة يان يون ،
You've been teaching me how to order soldiers on the battlefield,
لقد علمتني كيف أطلب الجنود في ساحة المعركة ،
I don't care how hard it is.
لا يهمني كم هو صعب.
I never dare to shout tired.
أنا لا أجرؤ على الصراخ متعبًا.
Because I'm afraid I'll let you down.
لأنني خائف من أن أخذلك.
Now that I'm a fire gentleman,
الآن بعد أن أصبحت رجل نار ،
I'll do my best
سافعل ما بوسعي
to ensure Ba Song's safety.
لضمان سلامة با سونغ.
But if,
لكن اذا،
if you insist on
إذا كنت تصر على
killing my mother today.
قتل والدتي اليوم.
For all the things you've given me,
لكل الأشياء التي أعطيتني إياها ،
I'd rather have nothing.
أنا أفضل ليس لدي أي شيء.
Ouyang Leiyun,
أويانغ ليون ،
I, He Xinmei,
أنا ، هو Xinmei ،
The enmity between you and me in this life
العداء بيني وبينك في هذه الحياة
has been written off.
تم شطبها.
Mother,
الأم،
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو ،
Mr. Jin,
السيد جين ،
Mother.
الأم.
Do you want
هل تريد
something to eat?
شيء للأكل؟
No need.
لا حاجة.
Pan Jun,
بان جون ،
get out.
اخرج.
You know what?
أتعلم؟
Ever since the soil system was gone
منذ أن اختفى نظام التربة
and the family was destroyed,
ودمرت الأسرة ،
No one has been so nice to me.
لم يكن أحد لطيفًا معي.
I'm sorry
أنا آسف
for what you did.
على ما فعلته.
Let me propose a toast to you.
دعني أقترح عليك نخبًا.
If 10 thousand goes in alone,
إذا دخل 10 آلاف بمفردهم ،
only one can come out.
واحد فقط يمكن أن يخرج.
No way.
مستحيل.
Ziwu, you can't go.
Ziwu ، لا يمكنك الذهاب.
Pan Jun,
بان جون ،
my master asked me to go,
طلب مني سيدي أن أذهب ،
I have to
على أن
release Ziwu and Yan Yun,
أطلق سراح Ziwu و Yan Yun ،
Pan Jun,
بان جون ،
the contract says Ziwu who lives
يقول العقد Ziwu الذي يعيش
and dies together,
ويموتان معًا ،
Did we sign a contract?
هل وقعنا عقدا؟
Live and die together!
عش وتموت معا!
Wake up now!
أستيقظ الأن!
Yan Ying.
يان ينغ.
Calm down.
اهدأ.
Boss Jin's condition
حالة بوس جين
is not very serious.
ليس جديا جدا.
Will she pass out if it's not serious?
هل ستفقد إذا لم يكن الأمر خطيرًا؟
My grandpa is right.
جدي على حق.
I'm a loser.
انا خاسر.
I'm just a worthless person.
أنا مجرد شخص لا قيمة له.
I can't protect anyone.
لا أستطيع حماية أي شخص.
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
don't worry.
لا تقلق.
Mr. Jin will get better.
السيد جين سوف يتحسن.
Wait for me here.
إنتظرني هنا.
I'll go find Brother Pan
سأذهب لأجد الأخ بان
and find a way.
وتجد طريقة.
At Shin time today,
في وقت شين اليوم ،
Ba Song Garrison took over Ba Song
تولى با سونغ جاريسون با سونغ
and told the public that
وأخبرت الجمهور بذلك
another Zerg democracy
ديمقراطية زرجية أخرى
had moved to report to the camp.
انتقل إلى المخيم.
Reward me.
كافئني.
This move should be called
يجب استدعاء هذه الخطوة
"two tigers fight against each other" and there must be one injury.
"نموران يقاتلان بعضهما البعض" ويجب أن تكون هناك إصابة واحدة.
Am I right?
هل انا على حق؟
Now you, a tiger outside the city,
الآن أنت نمر خارج المدينة ،
can sit in Ba Song City.
يمكن الجلوس في مدينة با سونغ.
Wan Jiacheng,
وان جياتشنغ ،
you did a good job this time.
لقد قمت بعمل جيد هذه المرة.
It's a pity that
إنه لأمر مؤسف أن
Kim So-mi didn't kill Ouyang Leiyun,
Kim So-mi لم يقتل Ouyang Leiyun ،
It's okay.
انه بخير.
There's still a chance.
لا تزال هناك فرصة.
Master,
يتقن،
nearly 100 of our people
ما يقرب من 100 من موظفينا
died.
مات.
70 or 80 guns were damaged.
تم إتلاف 70 أو 80 بندقية.
Put the rest of you together.
ضع البقية معك.
I'll leave the rest to Yanyun.
سأترك الباقي ليانيون.
Yes.
نعم.
Master,
يتقن،
that girl named Duan Xiao'e is here to see Pan Jun.
تلك الفتاة المسماة دوان شياو هنا لرؤية بان جون.
I'm afraid Xinmei is seriously ill.
أخشى أن شينمي مريضة بشكل خطير.
She's the only one who came back.
هي الوحيدة التي عادت.
Yes.
نعم.
Let her in.
دعها تدخل.
Go back and get some sleep.
ارجع واحصل على قسط من النوم.
Let's take your place.
لنأخذ مكانك.
No, thanks.
ًلا شكرا.
I have to keep an eye on Ziwu.
لا بد لي من مراقبة Ziwu.
Don't wait for my son to wake up at noon.
لا تنتظر ابني أن يستيقظ ظهرا.
You look so pale
تبدين شاحبة جدا
that you fell ill again.
أنك مرضت مرة أخرى.
Alright,
على ما يرام،
I said I won't go.
قلت لن أذهب.
Pan Jun,
بان جون ،
you're too noisy.
أنت صاخبة جدا.
Ziwu, you're awake.
Ziwu ، أنت مستيقظ.
Let me tell you,
دعني أخبرك،
can you stop doing this next time?
هل يمكنك التوقف عن فعل هذا في المرة القادمة؟
Your life,
حياتك،
keep your voice down.
ابقي صوتك منخفضا.
I just woke up at noon.
لقد استيقظت للتو ظهرا.
Pan Jun,
بان جون ،
stop scolding me.
توقف عن توبيخي.
What will you say in the future?
ماذا ستقول في المستقبل؟
I'll listen to them all,
سأستمع إليهم جميعًا ،
everybody
الجميع
You're not hurt, are you?
أنت لا تتأذى ، أليس كذلك؟
You're such a fool.
يا لك من أحمق.
Which one of us can get hurt?
أي واحد منا يمكن أن يتأذى؟
As long as no one gets hurt.
طالما لا أحد يتأذى.
Yanyun,
يانيون ،
where's your grandpa?
اين جدك
My grandpa.
جدي.
My grandpa is fine,
جدي بخير
thanks to you,
شكرا لك،
I'm glad you're fine.
أنا سعيد أنك بخير.
Touch your hands?
تلمس يديك؟
Yanyun,
يانيون ،
I won't leave you again.
لن أتركك مرة أخرى.
God bless me.
ليبباركني الرب.
I knew Ziwu would be fine.
كنت أعلم أن Ziwu سيكون بخير.
I was so close.
كنت قريبا جدا.
I'm telling you, he won't be so lucky next time.
أنا أخبرك ، لن يكون محظوظًا جدًا في المرة القادمة.
By the way, how is Boss Jin?
بالمناسبة ، كيف حال بوس جين؟
After we left the arsenal,
بعد أن تركنا الترسانة ،
Boss Jin's health went downhill,
تدهورت صحة بوس جين ،
He has been unconscious until now.
لقد كان فاقدًا للوعي حتى الآن.
She has been unconscious.
لقد كانت فاقدة للوعي.
She has persisted for more than 20 years.
لقد استمرت لأكثر من 20 عامًا.
It can't be today.
لا يمكن أن يكون اليوم.
Pan Jun, let's go now.
بان جون ، دعنا نذهب الآن.
Let's do it together
دعونا نفعل ذلك معا
Let's go.
هيا بنا.
Miss Yan Yun,
ملكة جمال يان يون ،
the Wan Army's motorcade has arrived at the gate of our mansion,
وصل موكب جيش وان عند بوابة قصرنا ،
The servants all say that
كل العبيد يقولون ذلك
the sky of Ba Song is about to change.
سماء با سونغ على وشك التغيير.
With my Ouyang family in Ba Song,
مع عائلتي أويانغ في با سونغ ،
who dares to change Ba Song's life?
من يجرؤ على تغيير حياة با سونغ؟
Yanyun,
يانيون ،
how about this?
وماذا عن هذا؟
You stay and help your grandpa,
أنت تبقى وتساعد جدك ،
I'll take care of Boss Jin,
سأعتني بوس جين ،
Yan Yun,
يان يون ،
guard Ouyang Mansion,
حارس قصر اويانغ ،
To protect the people of Ba Song,
لحماية شعب با سونغ ،
you are now a gentleman of Fire Branch,
أنت الآن رجل نبيل من فرع النار ،
You can't leave.
لا يمكنك المغادرة.
Yanyun,
يانيون ،
listen to me,
استمع لي،
Now Ouyang Family and Boss Jin
الآن عائلة أويانغ وبوس جين
are hurting each other.
يؤذون بعضهم البعض.
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
The Wanjia Army
جيش وانجيا
will take advantage of it.
سوف تستفيد منه.
All right,
حسنا،
don't move now.
لا تتحرك الآن.
Okay,
تمام،
Then I'll stay at Ouyang's Mansion.
ثم سأبقى في قصر Ouyang.
Keep an eye on Wan Jiajun.
راقب Wan Jiajun.
I'm counting on you for everything about my mother.
أنا أعتمد عليك في كل شيء يتعلق بوالدتي.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I'll do my best.
سافعل ما بوسعي.
Let's go.
هيا بنا.
You two wait for me here.
أنتما الاثنان تنتظرانني هنا.
Yes
نعم
Greetings, Senior Lei Yun.
تحياتي ، كبير لي يون.
Greetings, Miss Yanyun.
تحياتي يا آنسة يانيون.
Congratulations, Miss Yanyun,
مبروك يا آنسة يانيون ،
for officially becoming a gentleman of Fire Branch.
ليصبح رسميًا رجل نبيل فرع النار.
Wan Jiacheng,
وان جياتشنغ ،
they all say that you are a general of the Wanchao Sect.
يقولون جميعًا أنك جنرال من طائفة وانشاو.
A young man is old and resourceful,
الشاب كبير في السن وواسع الحيلة ،
and what he said today is true.
وما قاله اليوم صحيح.
I admire you.
انا معجب بك.
Compared to you,
مقارنة لك،
Jiacheng is far worse.
جياتشنغ أسوأ بكثير.
Please.
لو سمحت.
After you
بعدك
Serve the tea.
قدمي الشاي.
This time, Jiacheng came here specially,
هذه المرة ، جياتشنغ جاء هنا خصيصا ،
because Mr. Ouyang
لأن السيد اويانغ
agreed to our battalion commander's marriage.
وافق على زواج قائد كتيبتنا.
Jiacheng is here to talk to you.
جياتشنغ هنا للتحدث إليكم.
In a few days,
في أيام قليلة،
our battalion commander will come to propose marriage in person,
سيأتي قائد كتيبتنا ليقترح الزواج بنفسه ،
There is such a thing.
هناك شيء من هذا القبيل.
Mr. Ouyang is officially in charge of the Fire Department,
السيد أويانغ مسؤول رسميًا عن إدارة الإطفاء ،
which is a happy event.
وهو حدث سعيد.
Senior Lei Yun defeated Kim So-Mei.
هزم كبير لي يون كيم سو مي.
This is Second Joy.
هذه هي الفرح الثاني.
If you can succeed in this matter,
إذا استطعت أن تنجح في هذا الأمر ،
it will be a triple blessing.
ستكون نعمة ثلاثية.
I'm here to congratulate Jiacheng in advance.
أنا هنا لأهنئ جياتشنغ مقدمًا.
As for this matter,
أما في هذا الشأن ،
we have to discuss it with Yanyun's father.
علينا مناقشة الأمر مع والد يانيون.
My father is still in your hands.
والدي لا يزال بين يديك.
Here's the thing,
هنا الحاجة،
Mr. Yanlei has been sent to Boss Jin's camp
تم إرسال السيد Yanlei إلى معسكر Boss Jin
by our battalion commander.
من قبل قائد كتيبتنا.
First,
أولاً،
Mr. Yanlei insisted,
أصر السيد يانلي ،
Second,
ثانيا،
it's our battalion commander,
إنه قائد كتيبتنا ،
I don't want to offend my future father-in-law.
لا أريد الإساءة إلى والد زوجي المستقبلي.
Are you going to be Commander Wan's lobbyist?
هل ستصبح عضو لوبي للقائد وان؟
Our coach gave you a lot of praise.
لقد أشاد لك مدربنا بالكثير من الثناء.
If you can cooperate with him sincerely,
إذا استطعت التعاون معه بإخلاص ،
it will be a blessing for the people.
ستكون نعمة للشعب.
It can keep the Southwest peaceful,
يمكنها الحفاظ على الجنوب الغربي سلميًا ،
isn't it beautiful?
اليس جميل
So,
لذا،
Yan Yun's marriage,
زواج يان يون ،
It has to be done.
لا بد من القيام به.
Senior said so.
قال كبير ذلك.
That means even more happiness,
هذا يعني المزيد من السعادة ،
Jiacheng will report it to the coach right away.
جياتشنغ سيبلغ المدرب على الفور.
No rush.
لا داعي للاندفاع.
I, Ouyang Leiyun, care about
أنا ، Ouyang Leiyun ، أهتم
reciprocity the most.
المعاملة بالمثل أكثر.
Don't worry,
لا تقلق،
our coach
مدربنا
will make a deal
سوف يعقد صفقة
that will satisfy the people of Ba Song,
من شأنها أن ترضي شعب با سونغ ،
Goodbye,
مع السلامة،
see off the guests.
توديع الضيوف.
Stop!
قف!
I'm looking for Boss Jin,
أنا أبحث عن بوس جين ،
Father,
أب،
You're here.
أنت هنا.
Where is your mother?
اين امك
It's inside.
إنه بالداخل.
Mei'er was tortured by the Zerg
تم تعذيب مئير على يد الزرق
to eat bones with thousands of insects.
لأكل العظام بآلاف الحشرات.
She was poisoned,
لقد تسممت ،
but no one found her body.
لكن لم يعثر أحد على جسدها.
That's why I believe she's still alive.
لهذا السبب أعتقد أنها لا تزال على قيد الحياة.
The redness on her left thumb,
احمرار إبهامها الأيسر ،
near the metacarpophalangeal joint,
بالقرب من المفصل السنعي السلامي ،
has spread to the entire back of her hand.
امتد إلى الجزء الخلفي من يدها بالكامل.
The poison developed.
تطور السم.
It's even better than I thought.
إنه أفضل مما كنت أعتقد.
So we have to get rid of the poison now.
لذلك علينا التخلص من السم الآن.
Well, Xiao'e,
حسنًا ، Xiao'e ،
heat a pot of hot wine,
تسخين قدر من النبيذ الساخن ،
-Heat the wine. -Yes. Hurry
- سخني النبيذ.  -نعم.  عجل
up.
فوق.
Okay.
تمام.
What?
لما؟
You're in a bad mood.
انت في مزاج سيء.
I saw Boss Jin
رأيت بوس جين
lying there just now,
يرقد هناك الآن ،
The first person that comes to mind,
أول شخص يتبادر إلى الذهن ،
is my mother.
هي أمي.
You know what?
أتعلم؟
The thing I regret the most in my life,
أكثر شيء أندم عليه في حياتي ،
is that I didn't learn to pick up a gun early
هو أنني لم أتعلم التقاط مسدس مبكرًا
to protect my mother
لحماية والدتي
and sister Shi Shi,
وأخت شي شي ،
Am I selfish?
هل أنا أناني؟
I hated fighting and killing since I was a child.
كرهت القتال والقتل منذ أن كنت طفلاً.
I just want to protect my family.
أنا فقط أريد حماية عائلتي.
I've been looking forward to it for 20 years.
لقد كنت أتطلع إليها منذ 20 عامًا.
In the end,
بالنهايه،
I could only watch my loved ones
كان بإمكاني مشاهدة أحبائي فقط
lose both sides.
تفقد كلا الجانبين.
I finally found my own mother.
لقد وجدت والدتي أخيرًا.
But she can only lie there.
لكنها تستطيع الاستلقاء هناك فقط.
Tell me,
أخبرني،
is it because I didn't point the gun
هل هذا لأنني لم أصوب البندقية
at the Zerg's real enemy,
على العدو الحقيقي للزرق ،
If it weren't for everyone,
إذا لم يكن ذلك متاحًا للجميع ،
then our little family,
ثم عائلتنا الصغيرة ،
It's just a small boat in the torrent,
إنه مجرد قارب صغير في السيل ،
which can be overturned by huge waves at any time.
والتي يمكن أن تقلبها موجات ضخمة في أي وقت.
I can't keep my dream,
لا أستطيع أن أحافظ على حلمي ،
and my family.
وعائلتي.
Yan Ying,
يان ينغ ،
it's time to pull yourself together.
حان الوقت لتجمع نفسك.
Department of Wood has superb medical skills. Thank you.
يتمتع قسم الخشب بمهارات طبية رائعة.  شكرًا لك.
If my father were here,
لو كان والدي هنا
it would be better.
سيكون من الأفضل.
The hot wine is here.
النبيذ الساخن هنا.
Mei'er.
مئير.
Mei'er,
مئير
you're awake.
انت مستيقظ.
Mei'er.
مئير.
Mei'er,
مئير
is that you?
هل هذا أنت؟
Yes.
نعم.
I'm Smoke Thunder.
أنا دخان الرعد.
I thought I would never
اعتقدت أنني لن أفعل ذلك أبدا
see you again in my life.
أراك مرة أخرى في حياتي.
I knew you weren't dead.
علمت أنك لم تمت.
Can you hug me?
هل يمكنك معانقي؟
You're a grown man and you still need a hug.
أنت رجل بالغ وما زلت بحاجة إلى عناق.
I'm sorry for Ziwu.
أنا آسف ل Ziwu.
Have you ever thought about giving up the treasure?
هل فكرت يومًا في التخلي عن الكنز؟
Far away from the world.
بعيدًا عن العالم.
How could I not have thought about it?
كيف لم أفكر في ذلك؟
It's just,
انه فقط،
Not now.
ليس الان.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
You don't want to give up the treasure,
أنت لا تريد أن تتخلى عن الكنز ،
you can't give up the Zerg?
لا يمكنك التخلي عن الزرج؟
The one who knows me,
من يعرفني
Miaomiao, is also.
Miaomiao ، هو أيضا.
Pan Jun,
بان جون ،
your choice,
اختيارك،
It's also my choice.
إنه خياري أيضًا.
Brother Pan,
الأخ بان ،
go and check on Mr. Jin.
اذهب وتحقق من السيد جين.
New Student Weekly,
طالب جديد أسبوعيًا ،
Journal of Geological Studies,
مجلة الدراسات الجيولوجية
The article published by Lianhe,
المقال الذي نشرته Lianhe ،
called Lu You Frozen to Death Bone,
تسمى لو أنت مجمد حتى عظم الموت ،
He is suspected of insulting officials at all levels.
وهو متهم بإهانة المسؤولين على كافة المستويات.
Exaggerate the disaster,
بالغ في الكارثة ،
confuse people,
يربك الناس ،
All the newspapers have been ordered
تم إصدار أوامر بجميع الصحف
to remove the false articles.
لإزالة المقالات الخاطئة.
If it's published again,
إذا تم نشره مرة أخرى ،
stop publishing immediately.
توقف عن النشر على الفور.
Who has so many things to do?
من لديه الكثير ليفعله؟
Catch him and kill
قبض عليه واقتل
the battalion commander,
قائد الكتيبة
You shut up the literati,
تصمت الأدباء ،
and don't let them vent their anger in the newspaper.
ولا تسمحوا لهم بالتنفيس عن غضبهم في الصحف.
They'll make a scene in the streets.
سوف يصنعون مشهدًا في الشوارع.
Go to the school,
اذهب الي المدرسة،
or even come to our door.
أو حتى تعال إلى بابنا.
Sit down and say that
اجلس وقل ذلك
there are a few literate people in this wild land
هناك عدد قليل من الأشخاص المتعلمين في هذه الأرض البرية
who can't even eat.
الذين لا يستطيعون حتى الأكل.
How many people can afford newspapers?
كم من الناس يستطيعون شراء الصحف؟
Who can be bewitched by this?
من الذي يمكن أن يسحره هذا؟
Let's just
دعونا فقط
let it go.
دعها تذهب.
Battalion Commander,
قائد كتيبة
this man's name is Gao Huaiyuan,
اسم هذا الرجل هو Gao Huaiyuan ،
It's a Chinese doctor living in Great Britain.
إنه طبيب صيني يعيش في بريطانيا العظمى.
Gao Huaiyuan,
غاو هوايوان ،
if he doesn't cure the disease and save people,
إذا لم يشفي المرض وينقذ الناس ،
After reading foreign ink for a few years,
بعد قراءة الحبر الأجنبي لبضع سنوات ،
he slandered us in foreign newspapers.
لقد سبنا في الصحف الأجنبية.
As for the disaster in Ba Song,
أما عن كارثة با سونغ ،
he put the photos
وضع الصور
of the victims in foreign newspapers,
من الضحايا في الصحف الأجنبية ،
The whole city is full of wind and rain.
المدينة كلها مليئة بالرياح والأمطار.
Ba Song,
با سونغ
if there's no one to pick him up,
إذا لم يكن هناك من يأخذه ،
I don't believe he made
لا أصدق أنه صنع
such a big noise alone.
مثل هذه الضجة الكبيرة وحدها.
Who took care of him?
من اعتنى به؟
Did you find out?
هل اكتشفت؟
I found out that
أكتشفت ذلك
Gao Huaiyuan had a close friend when he was abroad,
كان لـ Gao Huaiyuan صديق مقرب عندما كان في الخارج ،
The son of Ouyang Family Ouyang Yanlei.
ابن عائلة اويانغ اويانغ يانلي.
Ouyang Yanlei.
اويانغ يانلي.
My father-in-law
والد زوجتي
is interesting.
مثير للاهتمام.
What's more interesting is that
ما هو أكثر إثارة للاهتمام هو ذلك
Gao Huaiyuan is a false name,
Gao Huaiyuan هو اسم مستعار ،
Can you finish it all at once?
هل يمكنك إنهاء كل ذلك مرة واحدة؟
He's most likely a member of the Zerg Clan,
إنه على الأرجح عضو في عشيرة الزرج ،
Pan Yingxuan.
عموم Yingxuan.
It's too much trouble for you to send telegrams
إنها مشكلة كبيرة بالنسبة لك لإرسال البرقيات
to an old man. I don't want to take care of it anymore.
لرجل عجوز.  لا أريد أن أعتني به بعد الآن.
You should hurry up with that herbalist's trial.
يجب أن تسرع في محاكمة المعالج بالأعشاب.
Get out of the way!
ابتعد عن الطريق!
Looks like
يشبه
I underestimated the Bone Devouring Poison of Thousand Insects.
لقد قللت من شأن السم المفترس لآلاف الحشرات.
Now I can only try my best to help Boss Jin,
الآن يمكنني فقط أن أبذل قصارى جهدي لمساعدة بوس جين ،
buy more time,
شراء المزيد من الوقت ،
If my father were here,
لو كان والدي هنا
there would be a better way.
سيكون هناك طريقة أفضل.
I have another idea.
لدي فكرة أخرى.
It just needs to be verified.
انها فقط بحاجة الى التحقق منها.
What?
لما؟
The blood of the herbalist,
دم المعالج
Yes.
نعم.
It was mentioned in the Tiangong Collection,
تم ذكره في مجموعة Tiangong ،
saying that the blood of Master of Human Resources and Grassland can cure all poisons.
قائلا أن دماء ماجستير الموارد البشرية والأراضي العشبية يمكنها علاج جميع السموم.
However,
لكن،
there are no records of successful cases.
لا توجد سجلات الحالات الناجحة.
It's no use talking about it now.
لا فائدة من الحديث عنها الآن.
Ziwu is still lying in bed and can't get down.
لا يزال Ziwu مستلقيًا على السرير ولا يمكنه النزول.
Who's going to test the herbalist?
من الذي سيختبر المعالج بالأعشاب؟
Jiacheng,
جياتشنغ ،
Shuai,
شواي
Pan Jun can be destroyed by just one wood department.
يمكن تدمير Pan Jun بواسطة قسم خشب واحد فقط.
Jin Sumei is competing with Ouyang Family's two tigers,
جين سومي يتنافس مع نمرين من عائلة أويانغ ،
so he doesn't have to stay anymore.
لذلك ليس عليه البقاء بعد الآن.
Do you have something on your mind?
هل تفكر في شيء ما؟
Yanyun,
يانيون ،
where did your marriage with that smoker Wanhushan
أين زواجك مع ذلك المدخن وانوشان
come from?
يأتي من؟
I promised to marry Wan Hushan from the beginning,
لقد وعدت أن أتزوج وان حوشان منذ البداية ،
which was a delaying tactic.
وهو ما كان تكتيكًا للمماطلة.
I want to keep it safe.
أريد أن أحافظ عليها بأمان.
Only Ouyang Mansion
قصر أويانغ فقط
is a life-long event.
هو حدث مدى الحياة.
How can it be used as a game?
كيف يمكن استخدامها كلعبة؟
My granddaughter won the bet this time,
فازت حفيدتي بالرهان هذه المرة ،
but on your birthday banquet,
ولكن في مأدبة عيد ميلادك ،
The Wan Army has been standing still,
كان جيش وان لا يزال قائما ،
Grandpa,
الجد
These things
هذه الاشياء
are not important to me anymore.
ليست مهمة بالنسبة لي بعد الآن.
You've grown up.
لقد كبرت.
You've learned to keep me in suspense. Grandpa
لقد تعلمت أن تجعلني في حالة تشويق.  الجد
and granddaughter are no longer children.
وحفيدة لم تعد أطفالا.
Grandpa,
الجد
how should we deal with the Wan Army now?
كيف نتعامل مع جيش وان الآن؟
is the most important thing.
هو أهم شيء.
Yes,
نعم،
I'd like to recommend someone to you,
أود أن أوصي بشخص ما لك ،
It can balance the ten thousand armies.
يمكنها أن توازن بين عشرة آلاف جيوش.
If you have this kind of talent,
إذا كان لديك هذا النوع من المواهب ،
tell me about it.
حدثني عنها.
How about Mr. Ouyang buying me a drink?
ماذا عن السيد أويانغ يشتري لي مشروبًا؟